(
"ai_sub_version": "1.9.2",
"subtitles_prompt_version": 2,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": "gemini-cli:gemini-3-flash-preview",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"gemini_cli": (
"timeout": 600
)
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": true,
"fps": 1,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"encoder": "libx264"
)
),
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"subtitles": 8
),
"retry": (
"run": 3,
"max": 9,
"delay": 30
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": false,
"scrub": true
)
4.22(Fri) 21:00
3D LIVE
バーチャルアイドルが踊ってみた！
天音かなた
ゲストは5人来るよ!!
4.22(Fri) 21:00
3D LIVE
Virtual Idol Tried Dancing!
Amane Kanata
5 guests are coming!!
剥がれ落ちたメイク　すっぴんのアニマル
Makeup peeled off, a bare animal
醜くてもやっちゃうのよ
I'll do it even if it's ugly
おすわりとかできない　だって待ってもできない
I can't sit, because I can't wait either
喉鳴らして行っちゃうまで
Until I go purring
イェーイ！始まったぞ！おたおめライブ！フー！
Yeah! It's started! Birthday live! Whoo!
みんな盛り上がって！行くぞ！
Everyone get excited! Let's go!
ガブッとしよっか　高まるビート
Shall we take a bite? The rising beat
良いも悪いも全然しよ
Let's do good and bad things altogether
はまってみよっか　突破するゲート
Shall we get hooked? The gate to break through
愛に期待は禁物だよ
Don't expect anything from love
ねえ止まれないほど狂いたい
Hey, I want to go crazy enough that I can't stop
心真っ赤にしてどうしちゃったの
What happened to my heart turning bright red?
痛みすらもし愛せたら
If I could even love the pain
あたしは幸せです
I'd be happy
剥がれ落ちたメイク　すっぴんのアニマル
Makeup peeled off, a bare animal
醜くてもやっちゃうのよ
I'll do it even if it's ugly
おすわりとかできない　だって待ってもできない
I can't sit, because I can't wait either
喉鳴らして行っちゃうまで
Until I go purring
牙を出し叫べ　ずっきゅんだ
Show your fangs and scream. It's a "zukkyun"
あたしは噛みついたら離さないや
Once I bite, I won't let go
剥がれ落ちたメイク　すっぴんのアニマル
Makeup peeled off, a bare animal
醜くてもやっちゃうのよ
I'll do it even if it's ugly
アガッちゃってよ　狂っちゃってよ
Get excited, go crazy
メグッちゃってよ　ンパッパッパッパ
Go around, n-pa-pa-pa-pa
アガッちゃってよ　狂っちゃってよ
Get excited, go crazy
メグッちゃってよ　ンパッパッパッパ
Go around, n-pa-pa-pa-pa
いやいや喰らい甲斐なくってつまんない
No no, it's boring because it wasn't worth eating
せめてちょっと拒んでほしかったわ
I wanted you to resist at least a little
少しだけ欲張れるなら
If I could be a little greedy
あたしは幸せになりたいです
I want to be happy
剥がれ落ちたメイク　すっぴんのアニマル
Makeup peeled off, a bare animal
醜くてもやっちゃうのよ
I'll do it even if it's ugly
おすわりとかできない　だって待ってもできない
I can't sit, because I can't wait either
喉鳴らして行っちゃうまで
Until I go purring
塗り重ねたメイク　ぱっちりのアニマル
Layered makeup, a bright-eyed animal
目を開いて待ってるのよ
I'm waiting with my eyes open
おすわりとかできない　だって待ってもできない
I can't sit, because I can't wait either
喉鳴らして行っちゃうまで
Until I go purring
牙を出し叫べ　ずっきゅんだ
Show your fangs and scream. It's a "zukkyun"
あたしは噛みついたら離さないや
Once I bite, I won't let go
塗り重ねたメイク　ぱっちりのアニマル
Layered makeup, a bright-eyed animal
目を開いて待ってるのよ
I'm waiting with my eyes open
にゃお　うにゃお　しゃしゃしゃしゃしゃ
Nyao, unyao, sha-sha-sha-sha-sha
にゃーす　うーにゃす　しゃーしゃーしゃー
Nyas, u-nyas, sha-sha-sha
お願いマッスル　めちゃモテたい
Please Muscle, I want to be so popular
お願いマッスル　めちゃ痩せたい、YES
Please Muscle, I want to lose so much weight, YES
お願いマッスル　めちゃモテたいから
Please Muscle, because I want to be so popular
ウー！ (キレてるよ！)
Woo! (Looking sharp!)
ハー！ (キレてるよ！)
Hah! (Looking sharp!)
筋肉にお願い！
Pray to the muscles!
ヒッププレス！サイドベント！
Hip press! Side bend!
(腹筋 6LDK かい！)
(Are your abs a 6LDK?!)
ダンベルカール！ハンマーカール！
Dumbbell curl! Hammer curl!
(二頭がいいね！チョモランマ！)
(Biceps looking good! Mount Everest!)
プッシュアップ！ベンチプレス！
Push-up! Bench press!
(大胸筋が歩いてる！)
(Your pectorals are walking!)
(仕上がってるよ！仕上がってるよ！筋肉本舗！はいズドーン！)
(You're ripped! You're ripped! Muscle Honpo! Bang!)
理想の自分を思い描いたら
Once you've visualized your ideal self
今すぐ始めよう！トレーニング！
Let's start right now! Training!
ヤバめの現実なんとかなるはず
You should be able to do something about the dire reality
ダンベル両手にフリーウェイト！
Free weights with dumbbells in both hands!
焦りは禁物、無理しちゃ沈没
Don't rush, overdoing it will sink you
負荷のかけ方を調節！
Adjust the way you apply the load!
限界 10回ギリギリ全開！
Limit of 10 reps, full throttle at the edge!
3セットしたらオーライ！
3 sets and you're all right!
辛いことある筋肉道
The muscle path has its hardships
モテモテボディがほしいの！
I want a popular body!
綺麗なワタシに大変身
Transform into a beautiful me
(さい！さい！さい！さい！さい！さい！)
(Sai! Sai! Sai! Sai! Sai! Sai!)
(はい、サイドチェストー！)
(Yes, side chest!)
お願いマッスル　めちゃモテたい
Please Muscle, I want to be so popular
お願いマッスル　めちゃ痩せたい、YES
Please Muscle, I want to lose so much weight, YES
お願いマッスル　めちゃモテたいから
Please Muscle, because I want to be so popular
ウー！ (キレてるよ！) ハー！ (キレてるよ！)
Woo! (Looking sharp!) Hah! (Looking sharp!)
筋肉にお願い！
Pray to the muscles!
レッグカール！バックリフト！
Leg curl! Back lift!
(泣く子も黙る大腿筋！)
(Quadriceps that'll silence a crying child!)
バックプレス！サイドレイズ！
Back press! Side raise!
(肩にちっちゃい重機のせてんのかい！)
(Do you have small heavy machinery on your shoulders?!)
ベントオーバー！ラットプルダウン！
Bent over! Lat pulldown!
(背中に鬼神が宿ってる！)
(An ogre god dwells in your back!)
(仕上がってるよ！仕上がってるよ！頑張るあなたは美しい！)
(You're ripped! You're ripped! You, who works hard, are beautiful!)
昨日の今日では効果出なくても
Even if you don't see results from yesterday to today
とにかく続けよトレーニング
Just keep on training anyway
気分を変えたい？混みすぎてツライ？
Want to change your mood? Hard because it's too crowded?
それならマシンでワークアウト！
Then work out with the machines!
食べるの大切、筋肉の秘訣
Eating is important, the secret of muscles
食事で体を建設！
Build your body with meals!
3日に1回、週に2～3回
Once every 3 days, 2 or 3 times a week
無理ないペースでオッケー！
A reasonable pace is okay!
めげそうな時思い出して
When you feel like giving up, remember
努力が実になれば、魅力
If effort bears fruit, it's charm
見せつけたいでしょ脚線美
You want to show off your beautiful leg lines, don't you?
頑張ります！ます？ます？ます？はい、モストマスキュラーー！
I'll do my best! Best? Best? Best? Yes, Most Muscular!
お願いマッスル　めちゃモテたい
Please Muscle, I want to be so popular
お願いマッスル　めちゃ痩せたい、YES
Please Muscle, I want to lose so much weight, YES
お願いマッスル　めちゃモテたいから
Please Muscle, because I want to be so popular
ウー！ (キレてるよ！) ハー！ (キレてるよ！)
Woo! (Looking sharp!) Hah! (Looking sharp!)
筋肉にお願い！
Pray to the muscles!
いくよー！今から私とトレーニング！
Here we go! Train with me now!
足を肩幅分開いたら
Open your feet shoulder-width apart
両手は頭の後ろにあげて
Raise both hands behind your head
片足を軽く上げたら準備はオッケー
Once you lightly raise one leg, you're ready
It's セットポジション！
It's set position!
上げた足と逆の肘を
Bring the raised leg and opposite elbow
くっつけるように腹筋を
towards each other to flex your abs
収縮！収縮！収縮！収縮！
Contract! Contract! Contract! Contract!
できたら戻して逆側も
If you can, return and do the other side
足と足と逆の肘を
Feet and feet and opposite elbow
くっつけるように腹筋を
towards each other to flex your abs
収縮！収縮！収縮！収縮！
Contract! Contract! Contract! Contract!
できたら戻してもう 1回！
If you can, return and one more time!
足と足と逆の肘を
Feet and feet and opposite elbow
くっつけるように腹筋を
towards each other to flex your abs
収縮！収縮！収縮！収縮！
Contract! Contract! Contract! Contract!
筋肉に、筋肉に、お願いだ！
To the muscles, to the muscles, I pray!
はい、サイドチェストー！
Yes, side chest!
お願いマッスル　めちゃモテたい
Please Muscle, I want to be so popular
お願いマッスル　めちゃ痩せたい、YES
Please Muscle, I want to lose so much weight, YES
お願いマッスル　めちゃモテたいから
Please Muscle, because I want to be so popular
ウー！ (キレてるよ！) ハー！ (キレてるよ！)
Woo! (Looking sharp!) Hah! (Looking sharp!)
筋肉にお願い！
Pray to the muscles!
ヒッププレス！サイドベント！
Hip press! Side bend!
(腹筋板チョコバレンタインかい！)
(Are your abs Valentine's chocolate bars?!)
ダンベルカール！ハンマーカール！
Dumbbell curl! Hammer curl!
(これが二頭の新時代...！)
(This is the new era of biceps...!)
プッシュアップ！ベンチプレス！
Push-up! Bench press!
(はち切れそうな大胸筋！)
(Pectorals about to burst!)
サイドクランチ！ハイクリーン！
Side crunch! High clean!
(出たね！プロポーションお化け！)
(There it is! A proportion monster!)
レッグカール！バックリフト！
Leg curl! Back lift!
(ザッツアグレート大腿筋！)
(That's a great quadriceps!)
バックプレス！サイドレイズ！
Back press! Side raise!
(とれ立て新鮮肩メロン！)
(Freshly picked shoulder melons!)
ベントオーバー！ラットプルダウン！
Bent over! Lat pulldown!
(背中に世界を背負ってる！)
(Carrying the world on your back!)
(仕上がってるよ！仕上がってるよ！頑張るあなたは美しい！)
(You're ripped! You're ripped! You, who works hard, are beautiful!)
お願いマッスルー！
Please Mus-cle!
らっしゃいな 平は成り
Welcome, peace is established
時が来た 正しい夢うつつ夜もすがら
The time has come, a proper dream or reality all night long
変わりゆくことに恐れなし
No fear of things changing
のっぴきならないのは御免
Unavoidable things are a no-go
手毬唄うたい
Singing a handball song
君たちが誘う
You all invite
やんちゃめ後ろ髪を惹かれても
Even if my mischievous hair is pulled back
進むべきなり
I must move forward
流行り廃りの憂き世なら
If it's a world of passing fads and sorrows
信ずる者はただ、君だけと
The only one I believe in is you
踊れ騒げや 呑めや歌えや
Dance and make a noise, drink and sing
案ずることなど何もない
There's nothing to worry about
此の世人の世は恨めしい
This world of mortals is resentful
雪駄はちゃっちゃっちゃ 愛し
Snow sandals go click-clack-click, my love
縋って梛んで満身創痍で それ それ それ それ
Clinging, bowing, battered all over, sore, sore, sore, sore
今を嘆いて昔を懐かしても
Lamenting the present, longing for the past
君の心の内 流る深河
Within your heart, a deep river flows
それじゃ敵わん 何処にいても
That won't do, no matter where you are
めくるめく舞台に君を連れて
Taking you to a dazzling stage
あまりてなどか人で悲しき
Too much, why is it so sad for a human?
身勝手なのが世の理か
Is being selfish the way of the world?
万人持つ理想 虚像の偶像
Ideals held by everyone, hollow idols
俗な答えなどはあつらえむ
I'll prepare some common answers
僕ら巡りあうこと まさに一期一会
Our meeting is truly a once-in-a-lifetime encounter
酸いも甘いも試練
Both bitter and sweet are trials
連れ添ってこの手握って
Staying together, holding this hand
生きづらい此処、浮き世から
From this hard-to-live-in fleeting world
旗を掲げよ 宵闇が明く
Raise the flag, the twilight brightens
酔いどれアガレヤ 憂えは忘るる
Get drunk and rise up, forget your worries
昔も今も変わらず
Unchanged past and present
浮世人の世は懐かしい
This world of mortals is nostalgic
いつだってちゃっちゃっちゃ おかし
Always click-clack-click, strange
荒んで笑って合縁奇縁で それ それ それ それ
Getting rough, laughing, bound by strange fate, sore, sore, sore, sore
深まる春も凍てつく雪の日も
Deepening spring, freezing snowy days too
日出ずるすべての瞬きを君と見よう
Let's watch every sunrise moment with you
彩る色 何処まででも
Vibrant colors, to wherever they reach
空前絶後の見晴らしを眺めて
Gazing at an unprecedented view
負けて花一匁
Losing, Hana Ichi Monme
欲しがる欲しがる欲しがる声
Voices wanting, wanting, wanting
勝てば恨んで買って選んで 呆気ないって泣いて
Hating if you win, buying and choosing, crying that it's over too soon
猿真似の何番煎じじゃ 満ち足りないの
Is it just a repetitive imitation? Not enough
おいなっそ おいなっそ おいなっそ
Oinaso, oinaso, oinaso
未だ進む道半ば哉
The road still goes on
おいなっそ おいなっそ おいなっそ
Oinaso, oinaso, oinaso
如何なる時も一歩前へ出せ
Always take a step forward
流行り廃りの浮き世なら
In this fleeting world of trends
信ずる者はただ、君だけと
The one I believe in is only you
踊れ騒げや 宵の歌えや
Dance and make merry, sing in the evening
案ずることなどないの
There's nothing to worry about
此の世人の世は恨めしい
This world of mortals is resentful
雪駄はちゃっちゃっちゃ 愛し
Snow sandals go click-clack-click, my love
縋って梛んで満身創痍で それ それ それ それ
Clinging, bowing, battered all over, sore, sore, sore, sore
今を嘆いて昔を懐かしても
Lamenting the present, longing for the past
君の心の内 流る深河
Within your heart, a deep river flows
それじゃ敵わん 何処にいても
That won't do, no matter where you are
めくるめく舞台は宵々、君を連れて
Dazzling stage, every evening, taking you
あまりてなどか人で恋しき
Too much, why is a human so longing?
身勝手なのが世の理か
Is being selfish the way of the world?
移ろうは古今 航路辿ら堂々
Changing is ever-present, following the route proudly
恐るることなどはあつらえむ
I'll prepare things for you to fear
Hey、こんかなたー！
Hey, kon-kanata!
2022年4月22日、天音かなたバースデーライブ
April 22, 2022, Amane Kanata Birthday Live
バーチャルアイドルが踊ってみた、始まりましたー！イエーイ！
Virtual Idol Dance Cover has begun! Yay!
で、今回「アニマル」「お願いマッスル」
So, this time "Animal", "Onegai Muscle",
そして「宵々古今」をお聞きいただきました。みんなどうだったー？
and you just heard "Yoi Yoi Kokon". How was it, everyone?
えー、ありがとう！コメント盛り上がってくれてありがとう！
Eh, thank you! Thanks for the hype in the comments!
今回のライブのコンセプトはずばり「ダンス」「アイドル」「かなたそ」となっております。
The concept of this live is "Dance", "Idol", and "Kanata-so".
12月の「リベンジ」というライブとはまた違ったかなたそをお送りするので、いっぱい、いっぱい、楽しんでいってね！
I'll be showing a different side of myself compared to the "Revenge" live in December, so please enjoy it to the fullest!
そしてみんな、今日の合言葉は…
And everyone, today's catchphrase is...
「かなたんしか勝たん」！
"Only Kanatan Wins"!
いっぱい呟いてね！
Please tweet it a lot!
それでは早速次の曲…
Now, without further ado, the next song...
ちょっとクールなあの曲を、あの子と一緒に歌って踊ります。
I'll sing and dance to that cool song with that girl.
それじゃあ、ミュージック、スタート！
Alright, music start!
'Oh my god'
愛のネタバレ「別れ」っぽいな
The spoiler for love, seems like "parting"
人生のネタバレ「死ぬ」っぽいな
The spoiler for life, seems like "dying"
なにそれ意味深でかっこいいじゃん…
What's that? It's so meaningful and cool...
それっぽい単語集で踊ってんだ
Dancing with a collection of words that seem like it
失敬
Excuse me
とう とぅるる とう とう とぅるる "風"
Tou tururu tou tou tururu "Style"
ぽいじゃん ぽいじゃん
Seems like it, seems like it
It's ish, right? It's ish, right?
とぅとぅる とぅとぅる とぅとぅる "風"
Tutulu tutulu tutulu "style"
神っぽいな
It's god-ish
もういいぜ もういいぜ それ もういいぜ もういいぜ
Enough already, that's enough, that, enough already
逆に興奮してきたなあ
On the contrary, I'm starting to get excited
おっきいね おっきいね 夢 おっきいね おっきいね
It's big, it's big, your dream is big, it's big
景気いいけど品性は THE END
Business is good, but your character is THE END
うええい うええい
Ueei ueei
"Gott ist tot"
"God is dead"
神っぽいな それ 卑怯 神っぽいな それ
It's god-ish, that's unfair, it's god-ish, that
"My God"
アイウォンチュ ウォンチュ IQが下がっていく感じ
I want you, want you, feels like my IQ is dropping
邪心っぽいな それ 卑怯 邪心っぽいな それ
It's devil-ish, that's unfair, it's devil-ish, that
アイヘイチュ ヘイチュ 害虫はどっち
I hate you, hate you, who's the pest here?
その髪型 その目 その口元
That hairstyle, those eyes, that mouth
その香水 その服 そのメイク
That perfume, those clothes, that makeup
アレっぽいな それ 比況 アレっぽいな それ
It's like "that", an analogy, it's like "that", that
その名言 その意見 その批評
That quote, that opinion, that criticism
そのカリスマ そのギャグ そのセンス
That charisma, that gag, that sense
神っぽいな それ 卑怯
It's god-ish, that's unfair
ぽいな ぽいな ぽい 憧れちゃう！
It's ish, ish, ish, I'm starting to admire it!
とぅとぅる とぅとぅる とぅとぅる "風"
Tutulu tutulu tutulu "style"
ぽいじゃん ぽいじゃん
It's ish, right? It's ish, right?
とぅとぅる とぅとぅる とぅとぅる "風"
Tutulu tutulu tutulu "style"
神っぽいな
It's god-ish
メタ思考する本質は悪意？
Is the essence of meta-thinking malice?
人を小馬鹿にしたような作為
Intentional acts like looking down on people
無為に生き延びるのは難しい
It's hard to survive idly
権力に飲まれて揺らぐ灯り
A light flickering as it's swallowed by power
神を否定し神に成り代わり
Denying God and taking His place
玉座で豹変する小物達
Small fries who change their attitude on the throne
批判に見せかけ自戒の祈り
A prayer of self-reflection disguised as criticism
Do you know?
何言てんの？それ ウザい 何言てんの？それ
What are you saying? That's annoying. What are you saying?
意味がよくわかんないし 眠っちゃうよ マジ
I don't really get the meaning, I'm falling asleep, seriously
飽きっぽいんだ オーケー みんな 飽きっぽいんだ オーケー
Getting bored easily, okay everyone, getting bored easily, okay
踊れるやつ ちょうだい ちょうだい ビーム
Give me the dancers, give me, give me a beam
奇っ怪ね 奇っ怪ね それ 奇っ怪ね 奇っ怪ね
How bizarre, how bizarre, that, how bizarre
逆にファンになってきたじゃん
On the contrary, I've become a fan
ちっちゃいね ちっちゃいね 器 ちっちゃいね ちっちゃいね
It's small, it's small, your capacity is small, it's small
天才ゆえ孤独ですね かっけえ… かっけえ…
You're lonely because you're a genius, how cool... how cool...
Gott ist tot
God is dead
神っぽいな それ 卑怯 神っぽいな それ
It's god-ish, that's unfair, it's god-ish, that
超健康 健康 言い張って くたばっていく感じ
Insisting you're super healthy while dying away
ヤケっぽいな それ 卑怯 ヤケっぽいな それ
It's desperate-ish, that's unfair, it's desperate-ish, that
"My God"
もう哀愁 哀愁 エピゴーネンの比
Already sorrow, sorrow, a comparison of epigones
そのタイトル その絵 そのストーリー
That title, that art, that story
その音楽 その歌 そのメロディ
That music, that song, that melody
アレっぽいな それ 比況 アレっぽいな それ
It's like "that", an analogy, it's like "that", that
その名言 その意見 その批評
That quote, that opinion, that criticism
そのカリスマ そのギャグ そのセンス
That charisma, that gag, that sense
神っぽいな それ 卑怯
It's god-ish, that's unfair
ぽいな ぽいな ぽい 憧れちゃうわ！
It's ish, ish, ish, I'm starting to admire it!
とぅとぅる とぅとぅる とぅとぅる "風"
Tutulu tutulu tutulu "style"
ぽいじゃん ぽいじゃん
It's ish, right? It's ish, right?
とぅとぅる とぅとぅる とぅとぅる "風"
Tutulu tutulu tutulu "style"
神っぽいな
It's god-ish
愛のネタバレ 「別れ」っぽいな
A spoiler for love, it's "breakup"-ish
人生のネタバレ 「死ぬ」っぽいな
A spoiler for life, it's "death"-ish
すべて理解して患った
I understood everything and fell ill
無邪気に踊っていたかった 人生
I wanted to dance innocently, this life
エビバディー解体 思い出に消しゴム！？
Everybody dismantle, an eraser for memories!?
あれっ。
What.
ハイになる？ 廃になる？
Getting high? Becoming ash?
「はい」とは言えな〜い！！！
Can't say "yes" (Hai) to that!!!
おかしい世界 お菓子は消えちゃう！？
Strange world, will the sweets disappear!?
どうしよ
What should I do?
どうして！？ 「もあ」して！！
Why!? Do "more"!!
君らしくないね？
It's not like you, is it?
ソンな時代でいいよ
That kind of era is fine
僕らまだワンダー信じてるの
We still believe in wonders
No? Know!
おどけた色の鋭利な目盛り
Sharp scales with playful colors
悩まされすぎちゃって
Being troubled too much
寄り目になっちゃいそーね！！
Looks like I'll go cross-eyed!!
"どうして！？" "あして！！"
"Why!?" "Like that!!"
全部「だいすき」がいいじゃん！！
Everything should be "I love it"!!
みんなみんな笑っちゃえの渾身で
Everyone, everyone, laugh with all your might
宿敵 逆境 モンスター 呼んできたっていいじゃん！？
Rivals, adversity, monsters, it's fine to call them out!?
スットンキョウでサイキョウなセカイを！
To a ridiculous and strongest world!
どうにもこうにも救えない困難もいいじゃん！
Even difficulties that can't be saved somehow are fine!
みんなみんな救っちゃおうのポーズで
Everyone, everyone, let's save them with a pose
ちょっとやそっとじゃ潰れない 笑顔をどうぞ！
A smile that won't break with a little nudge!
100回落ちても不死鳥は 取り乱さない！
Even if it falls 100 times, the phoenix won't lose its cool!
ワン・ツー・スリー・フォー
One, two, three, four
エビバディ ショウタイム！
Everybody Showtime!
セカイ解体10秒前！ 待って待って待って
10 seconds before the world dismantles! Wait, wait, wait
まだまだ一生一緒の渾身です
It's still a lifelong "together" with all my might
101回目のそのメモリー敗者
The memory-loser of the 101st time
「ハッピー」も「失敗」も消さないから！！
Because I won't erase "happy" or "failures"!!
セカイ ウチュー ミライ ちょうだい好きでギュージャン！
World, space, future, give me them, love them, hugs!
みんなみんな笑っちゃえの正解は
The correct answer to everyone laughing is
宿敵 逆境 モンスター 何だっていいじゃん！
Rivals, adversity, monsters, whatever is fine!
スットンキョウでサイキョウな お菓子だろ？
It's ridiculous and the strongest sweets, right?
セカイ もう一回 もう一回 好きでギュージャン！
World, once more, once more, love it, hugs!
みんなみんなくすぐっちゃおのポーズで
Everyone, everyone, let's tickle them with a pose
ぜったいぜったいね 消さない 笑顔どうぞ！
Definitely, definitely, I won't erase it, here's a smile!
∞回落ちても不死鳥は 取り壊せない！！
Even if it falls infinity times, the phoenix can't be demolished!!
ワン・ツー・スリー・フォー エビバディ ショウタイム！
One, two, three, four, Everybody Showtime!
メルメル
Mel-Mel
カプッ
Bite
アキ先輩
Aki-senpai
ベリーベリーハッピー！
Very Very Happy!
NENEいっぱい
Lots of Nene
おめでとう！
Congratulations!
ねねちゃん、ありがとうございました！
Nene-chan, thank you very much!
でした！
That was it!
次の曲は、ちょっと準備があるので、しばしお待ちください！
For the next song, I have some preparations, so please wait a moment!
しばし待てよ！
Wait a moment!
よし、後ろ頑張るぞ！
Alright, I'll do my best in the back!
オッケー！
Okay!
よいしょー！
Yoisho!
怪我する...
I'm gonna get hurt...
頑張るぞ！
Let's do our best!
頑張るわ！
I'll do my best!
よし、それじゃ、次の曲、GO! GO! MANIAC! 行くぜー！
Alright then, the next song: GO! GO! MANIAC! Let's go!
やばい！ 止まれない 止まらない
Crap! I can't stop, I won't stop
昼に夜に朝に singing so loud
Day and night and morning, singing so loud
好きなことしてるだけだよ Girls Go Maniac
I'm just doing what I love, Girls Go Maniac
あんなメロディ こんなリリック
A melody like this, lyrics like these
探していきたいんだ もっともっと
I want to keep searching for them, more and more
みんな一緒にね
Everyone together
Chance Chance 願いを
Chance Chance, my wish
Jump Jump 掲げて
Jump Jump, hold it high
Fun Fun 想いを
Fun Fun, my feelings
Shout Shout 伝えよう
Shout Shout, let's convey them
ミスったらリハってことにして、もっかい！
If we mess up, let's just say it was rehearsal and do it again!
ハ！
Ha!
K A N A T A
びっくりマーク消して 行くぞー！
Erase the exclamation mark, let's go!
イェーイ！
Yay!
誰も持ってるハートっていう名の小宇宙
A micro-cosmos called the heart that everyone has
ギュッと詰まっているよ 喜怒哀楽や愛
Tightly packed with emotions and love
シュンってなったりワクワクしたり busy
Feeling down or excited, it's busy
カオス満載な日々を歌にしちゃおう
Let's turn these chaotic days into a song
ぶちまけあっちゃおう
Let's pour it all out
授業中も無意識に研究する musicianship
Studying musicianship unconsciously even during class
エアでOK 雰囲気大事
Air is okay, atmosphere is important
刻み出すリズム
The rhythm starts to carve
通じ合っちゃうビート マインド 自由にエンジョイ
Beats and minds connecting, enjoy freely
楽しんだもんが勝つ
The one who has fun wins
ごめん 譲れない 譲れない
Sorry, I won't give in, I won't give in
縦・横・斜めの swinging around
Vertical, horizontal, diagonal, swinging around
好きな音出してるだけだよ Girls Go Maniac
I'm just making the sounds I love, Girls Go Maniac
あんなグルーヴ こんなリバーブ
A groove like that, reverb like this
試していきたいんだ ずっとずっと
I want to keep trying them, forever and ever
息合わせようね
Let's synchronize our breaths
Chase Chase 明日を
Chase Chase, tomorrow
Break Break 夢見て
Break Break, dreaming
Faith Faith 強気で
Faith Faith, with confidence
Shake Shake 盛り上がろう
Shake Shake, let's get hyped
遊び心忘れらんないっしょ、喝采！
We can't forget our playful spirit, can we? Applause!
ホッ！
Ho!
ほんと現実はマジ奇なり 小説より
Reality is truly stranger than fiction
ボーッとしててもね ぶつかる出会い
Even if you're spaced out, you'll bump into encounters
キュンってなったりグサッときたり funny
Heart-throbbing or heart-stabbing, it's funny
これって運命？ じゅーぶん楽しんじゃおう
Is this fate? Let's enjoy it to the fullest
めいっぱい楽しんじゃおう
Let's enjoy it as much as we can
試験前も通常通り 引き裂けない friendship
Even before exams, it's as usual, an unbreakable friendship
約束してないのに ついつい集まる放課後
Even without a promise, we end up gathering after school
どこだってメンバー揃ったら大場所 即ステージ
Wherever the members gather, it's a big venue, an instant stage
聞こえるよね？ サウンド
Can you hear it? The sound
当然 笑顔だし 笑顔でね
Of course, with a smile, let's smile
春夏秋冬 stepping out, now
Spring, summer, fall, winter, stepping out, now
好きな仲間といるだけだよ Girls Go Maniac
I'm just with the friends I love, Girls Go Maniac
あんなドラミング こんなカッティング
Drumming like that, cutting like this
受け止めてほしいんだ どうかどうが
I want you to accept it, please, please
目合わせようね
Let's meet each other's eyes
Tune Tune ココロも
Tune Tune, even our hearts
Amuse Amuse 重ねて
Amuse Amuse, overlapping
Loose Loose 気楽に
Loose Loose, relaxedly
Shoot Shoot 技磨こう
Shoot Shoot, let's polish our skills
まだまだいけるはずでしょ、実際！
We should still be able to go on, really!
ハ！
Ha!
大人たちは言うけれど 好きなことばっかしちゃ
Adults say, "If you only do what you like..."
ダメになるって言うけれど そうかな？ どうかな？
..."You'll become useless," but is that so? I wonder?
ねえ 好きなことに夢中になってる瞬間こそが
Hey, the moments when you're absorbed in what you love...
生きてるって感じだし... 幸せだし... だからいいやつダメになるわけない
...are when I feel alive... and happy... so there's no way it'll make me a bad person
ナイス！
Nice!
シャ！
Sha!
やっぱし 止まれない 止まらない
As I thought, I can't stop, I won't stop
昼に夜に朝に singing so loud
Day and night and morning, singing so loud
好きなことしてるだけだよ Girls Go Maniac
I'm just doing what I love, Girls Go Maniac
あんなメロディ こんなリリック
A melody like this, lyrics like these
探していきたいんだ もっともっと
I want to keep searching for them, more and more
みんな一緒にね
Everyone together
Chance Chance 願いを
Chance Chance, my wish
Jump Jump 掲げて
Jump Jump, hold it high
Fun Fun 想いを
Fun Fun, my feelings
Shout Shout more
Chance Chance 願いを
Chance Chance, my wish
Jump Jump 掲げて
Jump Jump, hold it high
Fun Fun 想いを
Fun Fun, my feelings
Shout Shout 伝えよう
Shout Shout, let's convey them
気持ちいいから yeah アンコール、もっかい！
Because it feels so good, yeah, encore, one more time!
Oh My God!
No No music, No smile
No No friends, No life
All right! No No No stop going our way
We have a fabulous BODY, SOUL
Oh My God!
No No music, No smile
No No friends, No life
All right! No No No stop going our way
We have a fabulous BODY, SOUL
Oh My God!
No No music, No smile
No No friends, No life
All right! No No No stop going our way
We have a fabulous BODY, SOUL
Oh My God!
No No music, No smile
No No friends, No life
All right! No No No stop going our way
We have a fabulous BODY, SOUL & LOVE
アラー
Ahhh!
イェーイ！ やったー！
Yay! We did it!
幾つの苦も美観主義
Aesthetics of many hardships
愛の反戦 一人じゃんけん
Love's anti-war, solo rock-paper-scissors
運命と縛 見ないふり それも移転
Pretending not to see fate and bonds, that too is shifted
Now I know all about you babe
GETCHA!
作詞：KIRA/木のひこ 作曲：Giga/KIRA
Lyrics: KIRA/Kinohiko Composition: Giga/KIRA
I don't want the handbags, the money or the diamond rings
'Cause guys like you they all don't care about the little things
まあ Anyway 吹っ切れたわけで
Well anyway, I'm over it
棒に当たって映えたって圏外です
Even if I hit a wall and stood out, it's out of range
I'm moving on and I'm never ever turning back
around, around, around again
Now I'll go higher and I'll go higher
And you couldn't take me down if you tried
ばら撒いてた愛 取り返し撤退だ
Taking back the love I scattered, it's time to withdraw
Now I can finally open my eyes
そんで来世もっかい君への返品サイン
And in the next life, once again, a return sign for you
Getcha out my life boy I'll getcha, getcha, getcha!
待ちっぱなしの恋なんて
A love that's just waiting...
錠をかけ放り捨て去って
Lock it up and throw it away
'Cause I'm fine, I'm alright 君なしで大正解
'Cause I'm fine, I'm alright, it was the right choice to be without you
Getcha out my life boy I'll getcha, getcha, getcha!
(Getcha out my life boy, getcha out my life boy)
(Getcha out my life boy, I'll getcha, getcha, getcha!)
Oops! Deleted your number. All of my friends used to warn me about ya
Baby, I thought that I couldn't without ya. I got myself now I don't need no other (Ah yeah)
もう息も止まるトキメキすら無い今
Now there's no heartbeat or even excitement
酸素吸ってハイッ、ちょい浮いてくか
Breathe in some oxygen, and let's float a bit
I don't want the handbags, the money or the diamond rings
'Cause guys like you they all don't care about the little things
そう Everyday 自己愛は順調で
Yes, everyday my self-love is doing great
先手打ち勝ち賞金さらって babe
Striking first, winning, and taking the prize money, babe
I'm moving on and I'm never ever turning back
around, around, around again
Now I'll go higher and I'll go higher
And you couldn't take me down if you tried
ばら撒いてた愛 取り返し撤退だ
Taking back the love I scattered, it's time to withdraw
Now I can finally open my eyes
今までにはない待ちわびた最終回
A long-awaited finale unlike any before
Getcha out my life boy I'll getcha, getcha, getcha!
All the lies and every mistake
All the goodbyes and the heartbreak
枯れ切った涙さえ No more
Even the withered tears, no more
(It's Giga and KIRA)
You ready?
(Getcha out my life boy, getcha out my life boy)
Lets go!
Getcha out my life boy, I'll getcha, getcha, getcha!
匿ってた偽造ID 暴落した価値 four on knees
The hidden fake ID, value crashed, four on knees
円滑な生活reigns 流されてくスライダー outta way
Smooth life reigns, being swept away on a slider, outta way
盲目な愛が溶けてくアイスバー もろく弾け抜けたソーダ
Blind love is melting like an ice bar, brittle and popping like soda
からって No pressure not to press ya I'll Getcha
Because, no pressure not to press ya, I'll getcha
ばら撒いてた愛 取り返し撤退だ
Taking back the love I scattered, it's time to withdraw
Now I can finally open my eyes
そんで来世もっかい君への返品サイン
And in the next life, once again, a return sign for you
Getcha out my life boy I'll getcha, getcha, getcha!
待ちっぱなしの恋なんて
A love that's just waiting...
錠をかけ放り捨て去って
Lock it up and throw it away
今までにはない待ちわびた最終回
A long-awaited finale unlike any before
Getcha out my life boy I'll getcha, getcha, getcha!
'Cause I'm fine, I'm alright 君なしで大正解
'Cause I'm fine, I'm alright, it was the right choice to be without you
Getcha out my life boy I'll getcha, getcha, getcha!
イェーイ！
Yay!
お送りしたのはあくたんと「神っぽいな」
That was 'Kamippoina' with Akutan,
その次に、アキロゼ先輩、メルメル先輩、スバル先輩、ねねちゃんと
followed by AkiRose-senpai, Mel-senpai, Subaru-senpai, and Nene-chan,
「とんであわんだーず」と「GOGO MANIAC」
performing 'Tondemo Wonders' and 'GO! GO! MANIAC',
そしてそして新しい挑戦、もう一人のかなたと「GETCHA!」でしたー！
and a new challenge, 'GETCHA!' with another Kanata!
あくたんとの「神っぽいな」はね、歌ってみた動画が上がってるんですけど
For 'Kamippoina' with Akutan, we have a cover video up,
ぜひ一緒に踊りたいと思って今回声かけました。あくたんありがとう！
but I really wanted to dance together this time, so I reached out. Thank you, Akutan!
そして、とんであわんだーず。こちらはプロセカの曲とダンスをやらせていただきました。
And 'Tondemo Wonders'. We performed the song and dance from Proseka.
プロセカ指が千切れるけど最高です。
Proseka makes my fingers feel like they're falling off, but it's the best.
えー、今回のライブをやるにあたって、あの、フォーメーションがあって難しいダンスを踊ってみたいなってなったときに
When I was planning this live and thinking about wanting to try a difficult dance with formations,
思い浮かんだのがね、あの、４人だったんですが、みんな快く参加してくれました。
those four came to mind, and they all joined in willingly.
え、本当にめちゃめちゃ難しい振り付けだったけど一緒に頑張ってくれて嬉しかったです。
It was a really difficult choreography, so I'm glad we worked hard on it together.
そして、「GOGO MANIAC」は一夜限りのエアバンドを組ませていただきました。
And for 'GO! GO! MANIAC', we formed a one-night-only air band.
「かなたん」という強めの承認欲求を感じられるユニット名になってしまいましたが、
The unit name ended up being 'Kanatan', which feels like a strong desire for recognition,
そのせいで先程解散しました。
and because of that, we just disbanded.
でも、アキロゼ先輩、メルメル先輩、スバル先輩、ねねちゃん、心からありがとう！
But AkiRose-senpai, Mel-senpai, Subaru-senpai, and Nene-chan, thank you from the bottom of my heart!
そして、ラスト...
And finally...
というわけで、もう一人のかなたとGizaでした。
And so, that was Giza with another Kanata.
今回のライブの演出は僕自身が提案、監督しているんですけども、
I proposed and directed the staging for this live show,
ホロライブのすごい技術により、どれも素敵に実現していただきました。
and thanks to Hololive's amazing technology, it all came together beautifully.
Gizaといえば、カリオペちゃん、すいちゃんの『歌ってみた』のイメージがみんなあると思うけど、
When you think of Giza, everyone probably thinks of Calliope-chan and Suichan's cover,
英語を一人で頑張りましたが、どうだったかな？
but I did my best with the English parts alone. How was it?
海外ニキ、Hi, Honey! どうですか？どうだった？
Overseas fans, Hi Honey! How is it? How was it?
ありがとうございます。さて、ではそろそろ次の曲。
Thank you. Well then, it's about time for the next song.
ここからの3曲は、しっとりめの曲となっております。
The next three songs will be more mellow.
それではまず、こちらから聞いてください。
First, please listen to this.
One Last Kiss。
One Last Kiss.
初めてのルーブルは　なんてことはなかったわ
My first time at the Louvre, it wasn't anything special
私だけのモナリザ　もうとっくに出会ってたから
Because I'd already met my own Mona Lisa long ago
初めてあなたを見た　あの日動き出した歯車
The day I first saw you, the gears began to turn
止められない喪失の予感
An unstoppable premonition of loss
もういっぱいあるけど　もう一つ増やしましょう
There's already so much, let's add one more
Can you give me one last kiss?
忘れたくないこと
Things I don't want to forget
Oh oh oh oh...
忘れたくないこと
Things I don't want to forget
Oh oh oh oh...
I love you more than you'll ever know
「写真は苦手なんだ」でもそんなものはいらないわ
'I'm not good at photos,' but I don't need anything like that
あなたが焼きついたまま　私の心のプロジェクター
With you burned into the projector of my heart
寂しくないふりしてた　まあ、そんなのお互い様か
I was pretending not to be lonely, well, I guess we were both doing that
誰かを求めることは　即ち傷つくことだった
Seeking someone out was synonymous with getting hurt
Oh, can you give me one last kiss?
燃えるようなキスをしよう
Let's share a burning kiss
忘れたくても　忘れられないほど
So much that even if I wanted to forget, I couldn't
Oh oh oh oh...
I love you more than you'll ever know
もう分かっているよ　この世の終わりでも
I already know, even if it's the end of the world
年をとっても
Even as I grow old
忘れられない人
The person I can't forget
Oh oh oh oh...
忘れられない人
The person I can't forget
Oh oh oh oh...
I love you more than you'll ever know
忘れられない人
The person I can't forget
Oh oh oh oh...
I love you more than you'll ever know
吹いていった風の跡を　追いかけた眩しい午後
Chasing the traces of the wind that blew past, a dazzling afternoon
Beautiful world
Beautiful World
作詞・作曲：Hikaru Utada
Lyrics & Composition: Hikaru Utada
もしも願い一つだけ叶うなら
If only one wish of mine could come true,
君の側で眠らせて
Let me sleep by your side.
どんな場所でもいいよ
Any place will do.
Beautiful world
Beautiful boy
もしも願い一つだけ叶うなら
If only one wish of mine could come true,
君の側で眠らせて
Let me sleep by your side.
どんな場所でもいいよ
Any place will do.
Beautiful world
迷わず君だけを見つめている
I'm gazing only at you, without hesitation.
Beautiful boy
自分の美しさまだ知らないの
You don't yet know your own beauty.
It's only love
寝ても覚めても少年マンガ 夢見てばっか
Waking or sleeping, I'm just dreaming like a shounen manga.
自分が好きじゃないの
I don't like myself.
何が欲しいか分からなくて ただ欲しがって
I don't know what I want, I just want it.
ぬるい涙が頬を伝う
Lukewarm tears run down my cheeks.
言いたいことなんか無い
I have nothing I want to say,
ただもう一度会いたい
I just want to see you once more.
言いたいこと言えない
I can't say what I want to say,
根性無し かもしれない それでいいけど
I might be a coward, but that's okay.
僕の世界消えるまで
Until my world disappears,
会えぬなら
If we cannot meet,
君の側で眠らせて
Let me sleep by your side.
どんな場所でも結構
Any place is fine.
Beautiful world
儚く過ぎて行く日々の中で
Amidst the days that pass fleetingly,
Beautiful boy
気分のムラは仕方ないね
Mood swings can't be helped, can they?
Beautiful world
It's only love
もしも願い一つだけ叶うなら
If only one wish of mine could come true,
君の側で眠らせて
Let me sleep by your side.
Beautiful world / It's only love
Beautiful boy / It's only love
Beautiful World
It's only love
Beautiful world
Beautiful boy
It's only love
Beautiful world
Beautiful boy
中空の庭
Garden in Mid-air
ここは中空の庭
This is the garden in mid-air
空知らぬ雨で満ちゆく場所
A place that fills with rain the sky knows not of
世界がどんなに美しくても
No matter how beautiful the world may be
絶えず悲しみは降る
Sorrow falls incessantly
願う度に羽は濡れ
Every time I wish, my wings get wet
地上へと近づくの
And I get closer to the ground
重い羽を閉じて
Closing my heavy wings
そっとからだを包む
I gently wrap my body in them
ここは中空の庭
This is the garden in mid-air
涙が雨に還る場所
A place where tears return to rain
時には温度を奪われて
Sometimes the warmth is stolen from me
時には汚れた羽を濯いで
Sometimes I rinse my soiled wings
やがて知るの
Eventually, I will come to know
こんなにも強く
That I wish for tomorrow
明日を望んでること
This strongly
天辺が世界中に反射する
The zenith reflects all over the world
願いごとが叶う度
Every time a wish comes true
堪らなく寂しいの
I feel unbearably lonely
次の願いに会える保証なんてないから
Because there is no guarantee I'll ever meet my next wish
願う度に羽は濡れ
Every time I wish, my wings get wet
地上へと近づくの
And I get closer to the ground
罪を抱え羽を閉じる
Bearing my sins, I close my wings
いつか満ちる雨に溺れ
Drowning in the rain that will one day fill everything
声が泡へと変わっても
Even if my voice turns into bubbles
映る水面は光が射して
Light shines upon the reflected water surface
私を照らす
Illuminating me
ここは空にいちばん近い
This is the place closest to the sky
近い
Close...
雲の頂きだからね
Because it's the peak of the clouds.
はい、お聞きいただいたのはOne Last Kiss、Beautiful Worldのメドレー、
Yes, what you just heard was a medley of "One Last Kiss" and "Beautiful World."
そして昨日リリースされました、天音かなた3rdシングル『中空の庭』でした。
And that was Amane Kanata's 3rd single, "Mid-sky Garden," released yesterday.
えー、しっとり目の3曲だったけど、どうだったかな？
Um, those were three mellow songs, but how was it?
コメントもありがとう！
Thank you for the comments too!
え、メンバー限定の配信でね、エヴァンゲリオンの映画をみんなと同時視聴しまして、
Um, in a members-only stream, I watched the Evangelion movie simultaneously with everyone,
その後、歌枠で歌わせていただいたOne Last Kiss、Beautiful Worldをね、
and then in a singing stream, I sang "One Last Kiss" and "Beautiful World,"
みんなが沢山褒めてくれたので、自己肯定感が爆上がりしてライブでも歌ってしまいました。
everyone praised me so much that my self-esteem skyrocketed, and I ended up singing them in this live too.
えー、美術館の中を歩いているように見せる演出っていうのをね、ずっとやってみたかったので、
Um, I've always wanted to do a production that looks like you're walking through an art museum,
生で実現できて、スタッフさんやクリエイターさんに本当に大変感謝しております。
so being able to realize that live, I'm truly grateful to the staff and creators.
そしてそして、『中空の庭』いかがだったでしょうか？
And also, how was "Mid-sky Garden"?
え、昨日の夜0時にリリースされた新曲で、初めて聴いた人も凄く多いと思います。
Um, it's a new song released at midnight last night, so I think many people are hearing it for the first time.
え、曲は『ひぐらしのなく頃に解』のエンディングの『対象a』などを、
Um, the song was composed by bermei.inazawa, who composed "Taishou a,"
作曲されているbermei.inazawaさん、
the ending of "Higurashi no Naku Koro ni Kai,"
そして作詞は僕が世界で一番大好きなボーカル、やなぎなぎさんにお願いしました。
and for the lyrics, I asked the vocalist I love most in the world, Yanagi Nagi.
もうね、タイムリープして数年前の自分に、
I'm so moved that I want to time leap and tell my past self from a few years ago
こんな夢のような経験ができているというのを教えてあげたいと思うぐらい感激してます。
that I'm having such a dream-like experience.
もうこれもね、それもこれもいつもそばにいてくれるみんなのおかげです。本当に本当にありがとう。
All of this is thanks to everyone who is always by my side. Thank you truly, truly.
さあ、いよいよライブもラストスパートで、歌って踊るかなたそをその目に焼き付けて、
Now, the live is finally entering its last spurt, so burn the image of the singing and dancing Kanataso into your eyes,
もっともっと大好きになってね！
and love me more and more!
かなたんしか勝たん！
Kanatan is the best!
よし、それでは。ずっと踊りたかったあの曲。必死で、必死で覚えました。
Alright, then. That song I've always wanted to dance to. I worked hard, really hard, to learn it.
心を込めて踊ります。星野源さんで『恋』。
I will dance with all my heart. "Koi" by Gen Hoshino.
恋 / 作詞・作曲：星野源
Koi / Lyrics & Composition: Gen Hoshino
営みの 街が暮れたら 色めき
When the city of daily life darkens, it starts to take on color
風たちは運ぶわ カラスと人々の群れ
The winds carry them, the crows and the crowds of people
意味なんか ないさ暮らしがあるだけ
There's no meaning, there's just living
ただ腹を空かせて 君の元へ帰るんだ
Just getting hungry and returning to you
物思いついたら ふと見上げて思うことが
When I start thinking, and suddenly look up and think
この世にいる誰も 二人から
About everyone in this world, from the two of us
胸の中にあるもの いつか見えなくなるもの
The things inside our chests, the things that will one day disappear from sight
それは側にいること いつも思い出して
That is being by your side, always remember it
君の中にあるもの 距離の中にある鼓動
The things inside of you, the heartbeat within the distance
恋をしたの貴方の 指の混ざり 頬の香り
I've fallen in love with the mingling of your fingers, the scent of your cheeks
夫婦を超えてゆけ
Go beyond being a married couple
一度思い始めたら
Once I start thinking
ずっとずっと一途
Always, always single-minded
ずっと ずっと ずっと
Always, always, always
醜いと秘めた想いは色づき
The thoughts I hid as ugly take on color
白鳥は運ぶわ 当たり前を変えながら
The swans carry them, changing the obvious
恋せずにいられないな 似た顔の虚像にさえ
I can't help but fall in love, even with a virtual image of a similar face
愛が生まれるのは 一人から
Love is born from a single person
胸の中にあるもの いつか見えなくなるもの
The things inside our chests, the things that will one day disappear from sight
それは側にいること いつも思い出して
That is being by your side, always remember it
君の中にあるもの 距離の中にある鼓動
The things inside of you, the heartbeat within the distance
恋をしたの貴方の 指の混ざり 頬の香り
I've fallen in love with the mingling of your fingers, the scent of your cheeks
夫婦を超えてゆけ
Go beyond being a married couple
泣き顔も　黙る夜も　揺れる笑顔も
The crying faces, the silent nights, and the swaying smiles
いつまでも　いつまでも
Forever and ever
胸の中にあるもの　いつか見えなくなるもの
The things in my heart that will one day disappear from sight
それは側にいること　いつも思い出して
Always remember that it's about being by your side
君の中にあるもの　距離の中にある鼓動を
The things within you, the heartbeat within the distance
恋をしたの貴方の　指の混ざり　頬の香り
I fell in love with you, the touch of your fingers, the scent of your cheeks
夫婦を超えてゆけ
Go beyond being a married couple
二人を超えてゆけ
Go beyond being two people
一人を超えてゆけ
Go beyond being alone
ライブもいよいよ終盤になってきましたー！
The live show is finally reaching its final stages!
みんなまだまだ盛り上がっていけるよなー！
Everyone, we can still keep this excitement going, right?!
特者生存ワンダラダー！！
Special-Selection-Survival Wanderader!!
なぬっ！？　ビシッ　ボリッ　バシッ
What?! (Snap, crackle, pop sounds)
ツッコミも冴えて　本日快晴
My retorts are sharp and it's a clear day
マボロ…　ギュムッ　バキッ
Illusion... (Squishing and snapping sounds)
手にする全部　It's mine!　くれくれ
Everything in my hands, it's mine! Gimme gimme
適度にがんばろうか（ぜっか？）
Let's do our best moderately (Is that so?)
そんなんだっていいけどさ
Well, that's fine too
必死にがんばろうか（そうか！）
Let's do our best desperately (I see!)
それが僕らしいよな
That's just like me, isn't it?
ダサすぎじゃねえんだわ！
I'm not that uncool!
そんで貧ぼっちゃじゃねえんだわ！
And I'm not a poor brat!
うん万事がバッチリイケてるに決まってる！
Yeah, everything's bound to go perfectly!
(are you?) かなたちゃん☆
(are you?) Kanata-chan☆
どどん！前進上等！ちゃんと歓迎して
Boom! Moving forward is fine! Welcome me properly
(wonder-la-der-la) 高まれ
(wonder-la-der-la) Let it swell
海空創造　ちゃんと驚嘆して
Creation of sea and sky, be properly amazed
(wonder-la-der-la) 興奮しよう
(wonder-la-der-la) Let's get excited
僕が言うんだもん　本当にするんだもん
Because I say so, I'll really do it
現実超えろ未来　あー！
Go beyond reality, future, ah!
弱点も平気　スイッチでランチャー！
Weaknesses are fine, switch on the launcher!
すなわち特者生存ワンダランタDAY
In other words, a special-selection-survival Wanderanta DAY
(wonder-la-der-la) 楽しもう
(wonder-la-der-la) Let's enjoy it
面白がれること探しまえ　oven?
Search for things to find amusing, oven?
返事聞かせてくれ！
Let me hear your response!
右左なんかじゃない
It's not about left or right
決めつけて一直線
I've decided on a straight line
つまり企てらんだら発射オーライが
In other words, if you plan it out, it's all systems go
ワクワクすんぜしぇー！
I'm getting excited, shee!
初見のみんな、天音かなたは裏切らない。
Everyone seeing me for the first time, Amane Kanata won't betray you.
歌も配信も頑張るからまた遊びに来てね。
I'll do my best in singing and streaming, so please come visit again.
いつも見てくれるへい民のみんな…大好き。
To all the Heimin who always watch me... I love you.
「何だよそんなこと言っちゃダメだ、おばか！」
“What? You can't say things like that, you dummy!”
うわ〜すごい！ありがと〜
Wow, amazing! Thank you~
日々これ騒然で go my way!
Being tumultuous every day, go my way!
虎視眈々でいたいんだもん
Because I want to be vigilant
だって意気揚々いいだもん
Because being high-spirited is good
全方位におっふりアンテナ張っていなくちゃ！
I've gotta keep my 'offu' antenna raised in all directions!
いつでも心はちゃんと純粋で
My heart is always properly pure
(wonder-la-der-la) いたいな好奇心は絶えず熱心で
(wonder-la-der-la) I want my curiosity to be constantly fervent
(wonder-la-der-la) いたいなって
(wonder-la-der-la) I want to be...
言い聞かせるんだ　調子に乗ったら
I tell myself, if I get carried away...
すぐ飽きられちゃうから　あー！
I'll be forgotten quickly, ah!
タイトロープもどんとこいっせ
Bring on the tightrope walk
(wonder-la-der-la) すなわち特者生存ワンダランタDAY
(wonder-la-der-la) In other words, a special-selection-survival Wanderanta DAY
(wonder-la-der-la) しがみつけ
(wonder-la-der-la) Cling on
”努力とは最後まで諦めないこと”
“Effort means not giving up until the very end”
メモっておいて！
Note it down!
ホントはbaby　自信なんかないよ
To tell the truth, baby, I have no confidence
ホントはbaby　不安ばっかで泣きそうさ
To tell the truth, baby, I'm just full of anxiety and feel like crying
でもねbaby　挫けないって決めたの
But you see, baby, I've decided not to be discouraged
だからbaby
That's why, baby
挑戦したいよ　未開の天地　無限のフィールドで！
I want to challenge myself in uncharted lands and infinite fields!
ラスト行くぞー！
Last one, let's go!
前進上等 ちゃんと歓迎して
Moving forward is fine, welcome it properly
(wonder-la-der-la) 高まれ
(wonder-la-der-la) Soar higher
海空創造 ちゃんと驚嘆して
Creating sea and sky, marvel at it properly
(wonder-la-der-la) 興奮しよう
(wonder-la-der-la) Let's get excited
僕が言うんだもん 本当にするんだもん
Because I'm the one saying it, I'll really make it happen
現実超えろ未来 あー！
Surpass reality, future, ah!
弱点も平気 スイッチでランチャー！
Weaknesses are fine, launch with a switch!
(wonder-la-der-la) すなわち
(wonder-la-der-la) That is to say
特者生存 ワンダランダDAY
Survivor's Wonder-landa DAY
(wonder-la-der-la) 楽しもう
(wonder-la-der-la) Let's have fun
面白がれること 探し放題でっせ
It's an all-you-can-find search for things to enjoy
無限のフィールドで
In an infinite field
パンニングしなくていい
No need for panning
ど真ん中一直線
Straight down the middle
つまりこれが僕の答えなんだ
In short, this is my answer
胸を張れ！ 今を生きるその意味を
Hold your head high! The meaning of living in the now
明くる日もあくるくる日も 確かめ進め！
Day after day, keep moving forward and confirming it!
のあー！
Let's go-!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
やんないんじゃない、できないんだ！
It's not that I won't do it, I can't!
ラスト全力で！ 盛り上がっていくぞー！
Full power for the last one! Let's get pumped up!
あー近頃 巷で噂のダメ天使
Ah, lately, the good-for-nothing angel who's the talk of the town
ダメなとこはもう天使のパワーで
The bad parts, I'll just use my angel power
おぎなっていーく その予定さ！
To make up for them, that's the plan!
ねえ足りないの もっともっとあなたに気にしてほしい
Hey, it's not enough, I want you to care about me more and more
だけど注目されすぎたらビビる ディスコミュ系
But if I get too much attention, I'll get scared, I'm the non-communicative type
天使のリングの点滅は 切れかけてるけど
The blinking of the angel's halo is almost dying out, but
見方を変えればこれも アイデンティティさ
If you change your perspective, this is also an identity
なんて強がりさ 本当は曖昧な愛の感情も
What a bluff, in truth, even the vague feelings of love
あなたと探したいの
I want to search for with you
ねえ ダメ ダメ ダメ ダメなあたしを
Hey, me who's no good, no good, no good, no good
(もっと)
(More)
愛してね
Love me
太古の衝動に無気力な
Listless against ancient impulses
天使ですが
I'm an angel, but
ドキ ドキ ドキドキをあげるよ
Thump-thump, I'll give you heart-pounding excitement
あなたには
For you
ちゃんと見ていてくれるなら
If you'll watch me properly
やるよ多分
I'll do it, maybe
ダダダダ ダメ天使は
Da-da-da-da, the good-for-nothing angel is
ダ ダ ダ ダ 駄目ですか？
Is it, no, no, no, no, no good?
だけどまああたしは いいか！
But well, for me, it's fine!
やんないんじゃない、できないんだ！
It's not that I won't do it, I can't!
テストで良い点取りたーい
I want to get good grades on tests
でも頭がちっとも追いつかなーい
But my head can't keep up at all
日曜日だって早起きしたーい
I want to wake up early even on Sundays
深夜のネトゲがやめられなーい
But I can't stop playing online games late at night
やる気が無いとかそんなんじゃないんだ
It's not that I don't have motivation
やる気があってもできない仕様だ
It's that I'm built so I can't even if I do
しょーがないねって許してよ
Forgive me, saying 'it can't be helped'
エンジェルリングを頬張りながら
While stuffing my face with my angel halo
てかこんなあたしに誰がしたんだ
Anyway, who made me like this?
てかこんなあたしにあたしがしたのか
Or did I make myself like this?
しょーがないねって許してよ
Forgive me, saying 'it can't be helped'
エンジェルリングを頬張りながら
While stuffing my face with my angel halo
天使の翼は使ってない 飛ぶの怖いから
I'm not using my angel wings, because I'm scared of flying
「本気を出したら飛べますか？」 みたい顔はしている
I'm making a face like, 'Can I fly if I try my best?'
そんなハリボテの裏側に 隠した愛の感情が
Behind such a facade, the feelings of love I hid
あなたに笑ってほしいの
Want you to smile
ねえ ダメ ダメ ダメ ダメなあたしで
Hey, with me who's no good, no good, no good, no good
...いいですか？
...is it okay?
実際は一切の自信もないような 天使ですが
I'm an angel who actually doesn't have a shred of confidence, but
グル グル グル グルと巡る頭の中では
Round and round and round and round, in my head as it spins
あなたのことばかり 考えてるんだ！
I'm only thinking about you!
ダメ ダメ ダメ ダメなあたしを
Me who's no good, no good, no good, no good
もっと愛してよ
Love me more
もらった愛で飛ぼうと思うよ
I think I'll try to fly with the love I received
天使だから
Because I'm an angel
ドキ ドキ ドキドキをあげるよ
Thump-thump, I'll give you heart-pounding excitement
あなたには
For you
もっと好きになってくれるなら
If you'll come to like me more
やるよ多分
I'll do it, maybe
ダダダダ ダメ天使は
Da-da-da-da, the good-for-nothing angel is
ダ ダ ダ ダ 駄目ですか？
Is it, no, no, no, no, no good?
だけどまああたしは いいか！
But well, for me, it's fine!
やんないんじゃない、できないんだ！
It's not that I won't do it, I can't!
いや、でも努力はしました！
No, but I did make an effort!
みんな、ライブ見てくれてありがとう！
Everyone, thank you for watching the live!
天音かなた2022年誕生日記念グッズ、今年は凄いです！
Amane Kanata 2022 Birthday Memorial Goods, this year is amazing!
おしおママ描き下ろしの抱き枕カバー！
A body pillow cover illustrated by Oshio-mama!
そしてさとうぽて先生描き下ろしのフェイスタオル、
And a face towel illustrated by Sato Pote-sensei,
そしてステッカー、
and a sticker,
そしてそして！みんなが前に配信で欲しいって言っていた、
and, and! Something everyone said they wanted in a stream before,
天使の輪クッション！
the angel's halo cushion!
記念ボイスに関しましては、今回は塩対応でクールな天音かなた層ボイスになっております。
As for the memorial voice, this time it's a cold and cool Amane Kanata-type voice.
ドMのみなさま、いらっしゃってくださいませ。
All you masochists out there, please come and enjoy.
そしてそして！フルセット購入特典は、天音かなた直筆サイン入りです！
And, and! The full set purchase bonus includes a handwritten signature by Amane Kanata!
今回はなんと数量限定ではなく、無制限にてお送りいたしますので、
This time, surprisingly, it's not limited quantity but will be sent out in unlimited numbers,
欲しいと思ってくださるみんなに届くと思います！
so I think it will reach everyone who wants one!
今回も本当にライブありがとうございました！
Thank you so much for the live today as well!
この後はアンコール、歌ってみたプレミア公開『フォニイ』！
After this is the encore, the premiere of the "Phony" cover!
そして大ニュース！
And big news!
天音かなた、ついにフィギュアになります！
Amane Kanata is finally getting a figure!
続報はこの後Twitterにて！
More details will be on Twitter after this!
それでは、フォニイの方へ、レッツゴー！
Now then, let's go to Phony!